Dorcas Olaniyan Frontend Developer

Lagos,Nigeria https://www.linkedin.com/in/dorcas-olaniyan-

https://github.com/Mhizdhee https://dorcasolaniyan.netlify.app/

Profile

Driven and enthusiastic web developer with a strong passion for creating user-friendly, beautiful and exceptional web experiences. I'm proficient in Html, Css, TailwindCss, Javascript, React.js, Materia UI, Chakra UI,Git and GitHub. I'm committed to staying up to date with latest trends and technologies to ensure the best user experience. I possess good communication skill, hardworking, ability to work individually and as part of a team, with commitment to continuous learning and professional growth.

Education

| 2018 – 2019 Lagos, Nigeria | Master of Business Administration (MBA) University of Lagos |
|-------------------------------|--|
| 2010 – 2015 Ogun, Nigeria | Food Science and Technology (BSC) Federal University of Agriculture Abeokuta |

Work Experience

2023/07 - present Lagos, Nigeria

Frontend Developer

YellowDot Africa

- Built intuitive, responsive user interfaces by translating high-fidelity Figma designs into pixel-perfect components using React.js and Tailwind CSS, ensuring consistent cross-device performance and adherence to accessibility and web standards."
- Collaborated cross-functionally with backend developers to integrate RESTful APIs, ensuring seamless data flow and consistency across frontend and backend systems.
- Performed comprehensive end-to-end testing of web applications to identify and resolve UI bugs, API failures, and performance issues before deployment.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and responsive behavior across devices, optimizing for both mobile and desktop platforms.
- Actively participated in project kickoff meetings and sprint discussions to gather requirements, clarify tasks, and provide frontend effort estimations for upcoming projects.

2023/05 - 2024/12

Frontend Developer

P2vest Technology Limited

• ICS Report Integration on Rotura Dashboard

1. Collaborated with backend developers to integrate APIs, ensuring communication between frontend and backend systems.

2. Worked closely with other front-end developers to ensure seamless integration of front-end components.

3. Developed and integrated an ICS report portal onto the existing dashboard.

• Revve Dashboard

1. Collaborated with a team of developers to design and implement a user-friendly dashboard for Revve.

- 2. Designed transaction management table for the backoffice using React js and Antd Design.
- 3. Integrated frontend and backend APIs for seamless transaction processing, Implemented filtering, sorting, and pagination for efficient transaction management.
- 4. Developed frontend and backend APIs for tier management, Ensured scalable and secure tier architecture.
- 5. Collaborated with team members to ensure seamless integration and bug-free deployment

2022/10 - 2023/06 Lagos, Nigeria

Frontend Developer

Stutern (Stutern Graduate Accelerator)

- 1. Collaborated with the design team to implement user interfaces (UI) and user experiences (UX) using React.js, Tailwind CSS, and Material UI and translated design mock-ups or wireframes into functional web pages.
- 2. Implemented a modular components architecture using React, allowing for code reusability and faster development iterations across multiple projects.
- 3. Writing and maintaining clean, efficient, and well-documented code, debugged and troubleshooting issues that may arise during development or testing.
- 4. Collaborating with other team members, including designers, and backend developers, to understand project requirements and deliver high-quality front-end solutions.
- 5. Used version control systems like Git to manage code repositories and collaborate with other developers.

Skills

| HTML | • • • • | CSS | • • • • |
|--------------|-----------|-------------|-----------|
| JavaScript | • • • • • | React | • • • • • |
| Tailwind Css | • • • • • | Material UI | •••• |
| Chakra UI | • • • • • | GIT | •••• |
| GITHUB | • • • • • | Antd Design | • • • • • |